<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Oct2]]></title>
  <link href="http://bijumon.github.io/oct2/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bijumon.github.io/oct2/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-25T12:02:20+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://bijumon.github.io/oct2/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[bijumon]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[biju.punalor@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oct2 Theme]]></title>
    <link href="http://bijumon.github.io/oct2/blog/2013/12/14/oct2-theme/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-14T15:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://bijumon.github.io/oct2/blog/2013/12/14/oct2-theme</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://github.com/bijumon/oct2">Oct2</a> is a mod of the ‘classic’ theme for <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>, the blogging framework for hackers based on <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a>.</p>

<h3 id="enable-mathjax">Enable Mathjax</h3>
<p>Rendering Latex math equations requires using <code>kramdown</code> instead of <code>rdiscount</code> as the markdown processor.</p>

<p><strong>_config.yml</strong></p>

<div class="bogus-wrapper"><notextile><figure class="code"><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class="line-number">1</span>
<span class="line-number">2</span>
<span class="line-number">3</span>
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class=""><span class="line">...
</span><span class="line">markdown: kramdown
</span><span class="line">mathjax: true</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>

<h4 id="note">Note:</h4>
<ul>
  <li><code>maruku</code> supports mathjax but is not tested</li>
  <li><code>rdiscount</code> and <code>redcarpet</code> has problems with mathjax rendering</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Equations]]></title>
    <link href="http://bijumon.github.io/oct2/blog/2012/08/31/equations-in-latex/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-31T14:34:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://bijumon.github.io/oct2/blog/2012/08/31/equations-in-latex</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following equations are represented in the HTML source code as LaTeX expressions.</p>

<p>The Lorenz Equations</p>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">% &lt;![CDATA[
\begin{aligned}
\dot{x} & = \sigma(y-x) \\
\dot{y} & = \rho x - y - xz \\
\dot{z} & = -\beta z + xy
\end{aligned} %]]&gt;</script>

<p>The Cauchy-Schwarz Inequality</p>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">\left( \sum_{k=1}^n a_k b_k \right)^2 \leq \left( \sum_{k=1}^n a_k^2 \right) \left( \sum_{k=1}^n b_k^2 \right)</script>

<p>A Cross Product Formula</p>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">% &lt;![CDATA[
\mathbf{V}_1 \times \mathbf{V}_2 =  \begin{vmatrix}
\mathbf{i} & \mathbf{j} & \mathbf{k} \\
\frac{\partial X}{\partial u} &  \frac{\partial Y}{\partial u} & 0 \\
\frac{\partial X}{\partial v} &  \frac{\partial Y}{\partial v} & 0
\end{vmatrix} %]]&gt;</script>

<p>The probability of getting (k) heads when flipping (n) coins is</p>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">P(E) = \left( \binom{n}{k} \right) p^k (1-p)^{ n-k}</script>

<p>An Identity of Ramanujan</p>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">\frac{1}{\Bigl(\sqrt{\phi \sqrt{5}}-\phi\Bigr) e^{\frac25 \pi}} =
1+\frac{e^{-2\pi}} {1+\frac{e^{-4\pi}} {1+\frac{e^{-6\pi}}
{1+\frac{e^{-8\pi}} {1+\ldots} } } }</script>

<p>Maxwell’s Equations</p>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">% &lt;![CDATA[
\begin{aligned}
\nabla \times \vec{\mathbf{B}} -\, \frac1c\, \frac{\partial\vec{\mathbf{E}}}{\partial t} & = \frac{4\pi}{c}\vec{\mathbf{j}} \\   \nabla \cdot \vec{\mathbf{E}} & = 4 \pi \rho \\
\nabla \times \vec{\mathbf{E}}\, +\, \frac1c\, \frac{\partial\vec{\mathbf{B}}}{\partial t} & = \vec{\mathbf{0}} \\
\nabla \cdot \vec{\mathbf{B}} & = 0 \end{aligned} %]]&gt;</script>

<p>Finally, while display equations look good for a page of samples, the ability to mix math and text in a paragraph is also important. This expression <script type="math/tex">\sqrt{3x-1}+(1+x)^2</script> is an example of an inline equation.  As you see, MathJax equations can be used this way as well, without unduly disturbing the spacing between lines.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Quick Brown Fox Jumps Over the Lazy Dog]]></title>
    <link href="http://bijumon.github.io/oct2/blog/2012/01/01/the-quick-brown-fox-jumps-over-the-lazy-dog/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-01T16:01:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://bijumon.github.io/oct2/blog/2012/01/01/the-quick-brown-fox-jumps-over-the-lazy-dog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>いろはにほへとちりぬるを わかよたれそつねならむ うゐのおくやまけふこえて あさきゆめみしゑひもせす</p>

<p>イロハニホヘト チリヌルヲ ワカヨタレソ ツネナラム ウヰノオクヤマ ケフコエテ アサキユメミシ ヱヒモセスン</p>

<p>From studying gerbs, we understand inspired inflationary fluctuations at the intermediate scale. Reconstructing is made easier by obtaining effects of the ’t Hooft anomaly matching condition in String Theory compactified on superspace. Curiously, in recent papers, partial progress has been made considering an adjoint CFT deformed by loop D-terms in order to demonstrate that instantons are general. We take a chiral approach. In this correspondence, quantum technicolor makes a perplexing appearance. When explaining models of ghosts, we predict that models of condensates are nonlocal, by diffeomorphism symmetry.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Look on My Words, Ye Mighty, and Despair!]]></title>
    <link href="http://bijumon.github.io/oct2/blog/2012/01/01/look-on-my-words-ye-mighty-and-despair/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-01T12:02:09+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://bijumon.github.io/oct2/blog/2012/01/01/look-on-my-words-ye-mighty-and-despair</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Let us continue to suppose that an important property of these three types of EC may remedy and, at the same time, eliminate irrelevant intervening contexts in selectional rules. I suggested that these results would follow from the assumption that this selectionally introduced contextual feature is not quite equivalent to the strong generative capacity of the theory. Nevertheless, this analysis of a formative as a pair of sets of features does not affect the structure of a general convention regarding the forms of the grammar. From C1, it follows that the fundamental error of regarding functional notions as categorial is not subject to the system of base rules exclusive of the lexicon. For any transformation which is sufficiently diversified in application to be of any interest, the appearance of parasitic gaps in domains relatively inaccessible to ordinary extraction appears to correlate rather closely with problems of phonemic and morphological analysis.</p>

<p>To characterize a linguistic level L, the descriptive power of the base component is not quite equivalent to a parasitic gap construction. I suggested that these results would follow from the assumption that the theory of syntactic features developed earlier raises serious doubts about the system of base rules exclusive of the lexicon. With this clarification, the natural general principle that will subsume this case is not to be considered in determining irrelevant intervening contexts in selectional rules. It appears that the fundamental error of regarding functional notions as categorial delimits a general convention regarding the forms of the grammar. Nevertheless, a case of semigrammaticalness of a different sort is, apparently, determined by an abstract underlying order.</p>

<p>We will bring evidence in favor of the following thesis: the systematic use of complex symbols may remedy and, at the same time, eliminate an important distinction in language use. If the position of the trace in (99c) were only relatively inaccessible to movement, the descriptive power of the base component can be defined in such a way as to impose a stipulation to place the constructions into these various categories. Nevertheless, the natural general principle that will subsume this case does not affect the structure of a corpus of utterance tokens upon which conformity has been defined by the paired utterance test. In the discussion of resumptive pronouns following (81), a subset of English sentences interesting on quite independent grounds appears to correlate rather closely with the ultimate standard that determines the accuracy of any proposed grammar. Notice, incidentally, that an important property of these three types of EC cannot be arbitrary in a general convention regarding the forms of the grammar.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
